{"data":[{"question":"He said to me, \" Is Susan in a black dress? \" \n= He asked me ___ Susan was in a black dress.","a":"that","b":"if","c":"if that","d":"that if","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Direct speech is interrogative: indirect speech used \"if\" to replace interrogative form","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"The teacher said to me, \" What do you have in your hands?\" \n= The teacher asked me ___ in my hands.","a":"if I had","b":"what I have","c":"what I had had","d":"what I had","answer":"4","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e.\u00a0said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original\u00a0\n+What, When, How... may not change to imply interrogaive","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to me, \"Which do you like better, this or that?\" \n= He asked me ___ I liked better.","a":"if this or that","b":"whether that or this","c":"which of the two","d":"whether which of the two","answer":"3","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e.\u00a0said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original\u00a0\n+What, When, How, which... may not change to imply interrogative \n+Which of the two = this or that","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"She said to us, \" Don't tell a lie.\" \n= She told us ___ a lie.","a":"not to tell","b":"to not tell","c":"not tell","d":"tell not","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Direct speech is a imperative- Indirect speech: reported verb + to Verb","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"The doctor said to the patient, \" Don't smoke.\" \n= The doctor ___ the patient not to smoke.","a":"forced","b":"believed","c":"expected","d":"advised","answer":"4","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"I said to him yesterday, \" Please come early tomorrow morning.\"= Yesterday I ___ him to come early ___ morning.","a":"told, the next","b":"asked, this","c":"begged, the following","d":"advised, that","answer":"2","explain":"- Direct speech is a imperative-> Indirect speech: reported verb + to Verb\n\n- Tomorrow morning-> this morning","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to me, \" Let's go on a picnic next Sunday.\" \n= He _________ that _________go on a picnic next Sunday.","a":"suggested, they","b":"told, we","c":"suggested, we","d":"told, they","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Indirect speech: Let's - suggest; Me-I, we ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to her, \" Let's go swimming in the river.\" \n= He _________ that ___ swimming in the river.","a":"suggested to her, they should go","b":"suggested her, we should go","c":"said to her, they should go","d":"told her, we would go","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Indirect speech: Let's - suggest; her-she ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to me, \" Don't smoke any more- It is very harmful to your health.\" \n= He told me not to smoke any more ___ it ___ very harmful to my health.","a":"that, is","b":"because, was","c":"so, was","d":"saying, is","answer":"2","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e.\u00a0said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original\u00a0\n- Direct speech is a imperative- Indirect speech: reported verb + to Verb \n- Because: used to explain","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to me, \" Would you show me the way to the station?\" \n= He _________ me ___ to show ___ the way to the station.","a":"told, calmly, me","b":"asked, abruptly, him","c":"asked, politely, him","d":"told, with goodness, me","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Interrogative - indirect speech: uses \"ask\" as reported word \n- Would you show me: imply polite attitude \n- He- Him","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"}]}